THE HUSBAND
THIS SERIES IS FICTITIOUS
CHILDREN WERE FILMED SAFELY GEN AI WAS USED IN SELECT SCENES
Yeah.
EPISODE 11
Why did you want to see me?
You asked me
If anyone else besides me and Ha Jeongsoo
Is in the know, right?
The fetal stem cells.
Someone actually introduced the idea to me.
Was it Choi Chiung?
Wait.
You already knew?
So what now?
Who will save your wife if I die?
Who else do you think will save your wife?
Screw you!
All you had to do was take out Kang Taeju.
That's all you needed to do.
You just had to stick to the plan. Was that so hard?
I'm out of options now.
Anyway, that being said
I want you to get rid of my wife.
What? What did you say?
Get rid of my wife.
I'll pay you, okay?
I'll pay you 300 No.
I'll pay you 500 million won.
So please.
I said get rid of Kang Taeju, not kidnap Ko Seyun.
It's all the same.
Don't be ridiculous! How is this the same?
As long as Kang Taeju is out of the picture, right?
Why don't you just hang tight?
Hang tight?
How's that going to solve any--
Hello?
KANG, SUSPECT IN WIFE'S KIDNAPPING AND MURDER, ESCAPES
:cue
What the hell happened?
What's this about Taeju soliciting murder?
Say something!
That husband of hers went rogue.
I told him to kill Kang Taeju, but he kidnapped Ko Seyun.
What did you say?
You said you'd keep Taeju out of this.
I swear
Have you been after Taeju this whole time, not Ko Seyun?
I'm going to the cops.
You're the one who wanted Ko Seyun gone so you could have Kang Taeju.
Make sure to tell them that too.
978T 1863
And in our next story,
A factory shoot-out in Gyeonggi-do
Has left one police officer in critical condition,
And the whereabouts of the suspect, Doctor Kang, remain unknown.
As the suspect is armed with live ammunition
And is considered highly dangerous,
Police urge nearby residents to stay away from the restricted area
And to immediately report any suspicious individual to the police.
Shit.
EMERGENCY SERVICES
SAFE HOSPITAL WITH TRUSTED MEDICAL SERVICE
And get that woman out of here too!
Please let him do it.
Seyun.
Dad.
Let Taeju operate on her.
Seyun, that woman is a criminal.
Not just any criminal. She's the one who kidnapped you.
I know,
But I want to know why they did this
And why they kidnapped me.
I want to know the truth.
RESTRICTED AREA
The immediate crisis is over,
And her vitals are steady for now.
Good job.
Well done
Saving that woman. :cue
You said you'd pay up last time too.
Why do you keep making me come back?
I'm trying to pay you back, okay?
We're businessmen here, not a charity.
You think 300 million won is a joke?
And we gave you enough time, didn't we?
- Wouldn't you agree, Doctor? -  Sir, please.
Once this project is done, I'll get the money right away.
I just need a little more time, please.
No sense of money.
And no sense of time either, huh?
I'm tired of talking.
- You. -  Yes, boss.
Find out where his daughter's preschool is.
-  Yes, boss. - No, you can't!
You can't! Please, sir.
I'll give you your money!
I'll pay you back tomorrow! Please!
- Sir, please don't hurt my little girl. -  Get off me.
You'll pay for it if you do! I swear!
What's this about?
You need cash, right?
Sorry?
Yeah, I know. How much is the debt?
Three hundred million won.
Dr. Choi.
I'm actually in kind of a pinch right now.
Could you lend me some money?
That should cover way more than the debt.
Could you do me a favor in return?
Isn't it so tense at the hospital these days?
Is it?
Well, nobody talks about it, but everyone thinks it's weird.
They're only keeping it quiet because it's about Ms. Ko and Dr. Kang--
Hey, are you okay?
That was Dr. Ha, wasn't it?
What's wrong with him? Darn it.
Beats me.
Dr. Cha.
Are you at the hospital?
Going up. The doors are closing.
-  Dr. Ha! - The doors are opening.
- Oh, hello. - Going up.
The doors are closing.
Working late tonight, Dr. Ha?
Yeah.
Me too.
So
Dr. Choi said he wants to see you right now.
- He did? - Yeah.
I don't know what it's about, but he asked me to tell you.
He said to meet him where you talked before.
But the thing is, I'm on my way to meet Dr. Ko.
Well, Dr. Choi said it's pretty urgent.
Well done.
WING B :cue
Dr. Choi?
It'll be over soon.
Dr. Ha is dead.
Why did you kill him?
I thought you were just talking.
- I said why did you kill him? - You knew what was going to happen!
What, you didn't know I'd do it?
The cops will want to talk to you.
You know what to say.
Nothing's working out as planned. Not one thing.
That's it?
That's why you were going to kill my wife?
If only you had stuck to the plan, I wouldn't have had to.
Take care of it before things get any worse.
Kill Kang Taeju.
You'd better hurry.
Your wife's running out of time.
Watch it, man.
Shut your damn mouth.
Before I kill you.
All right?
Was it Choi Chiung?
How did you find out?
Someone had ordered Dr. Ha to kill Kim Gyeongae.
At first,
I thought it was you.
But once I realized that it wasn't you,
There was only one person left.
Someone who knew about the project,
Had access to potassium chloride,
And knew about Kim Gyeongae's record
And could use that information to manipulate her and her husband.
Choi Chiung.
He's still at the hospital.
I doubt there's any evidence left.
If there were, he would've escaped already.
So what do you plan to do?
You just have to act like you're completely oblivious.
Even with Seyun.
THE HUSBAND :cue
There you are.
Hey.
How are you holding up?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Good to hear. What about Seyun?
Well, she's still struggling.
Makes sense. It can't be easy.
So much happened in such a short time. Dr. Ha, and then Dr. Cha.
You know, speaking of Dr. Ha
Do you think he really took his own life?
What do you mean by that?
I mean, Myeonghui is on the run.
Plus, she was the last person Dr. Ha was with before he died.
So you think Myeonghui is behind his death?
Not necessarily. I just thought it might be a possibility.
I guess.
I assume she ran away for a reason.
If she had nothing to hide, why would she have run?
It's almost time for my appointment. I have to go.
Okay.
Chiung.
Yeah?
Could Myeonghui really pull this off all on her own?
Well, I'm sure the cops will figure it out.
Don't think about it too much.
Could Myeonghui really pull this off on her own?
There you are.
Hey.
How's it going, officer?
I'm here to check on her.
Goodness.
Dr. Choi, what are you doing here?
I saw the police just dropped by.
What'd you talk about?
They were asking about Dr. Cha. :cue
They asked if I knew where she went.
And?
I said I don't know. Because I really don't.
Well, then, what about when Kang Taeju came by?
Did you tell him anything?
Why?
Did he mention something?
I'm the one asking questions here.
I'm not sure what you mean.
Oh, about how you told us to take out Kang Taeju?
Or about our deal?
I didn't tell him anything.
I did exactly as you said.
I said Ha Jeongsoo called all the shots. That's all I told him.
Make sure you stick to that story.
Hey, Doctor.
Guess what?
The cops said they'll be back soon.
What I'll say then is up to you, isn't it?
I don't think you quite understand your situation right now.
Your husband's a wanted man, right?
And you're an accomplice.
The cops are only giving you a break because you're a patient.
So don't get any stupid ideas.
Ha Jeongsoo.
You killed him, didn't you?
Take care of yourself.
Yes, exactly. But I'm sure there'll be cameras, so
Yeah, if you keep searching, I'm sure you'll find them.
I'd suggest you look into those.
I'll get in touch if we find anything.
- Okay. - All right.
Hey, Chiung.
What is it again?
Is something going on?
Nothing. It's just
I remembered something while I was talking to you earlier.
What?
The day Dr. Ha died
I thought someone might've snuck in and out through the fire doors.
I told them, and they said they'd check the footage.
Yeah, of course they should look into it.
Yes.
Yeah, maybe they'll find something.
Did the cameras capture my car?
No. It's fine.
But why would he bring that up out of nowhere?
Kang Taeju.
You've been the problem all along.
:cue
Hi.
Dr. Choi.
Yeah?
There's been a change of plans for today's surgery.
What change? What are you talking about?
Dr. Kang will be leading the surgery.
It's Dr. Ko's orders.
The fetal stem cell cultures are ready for the next procedure.
Hmm.
The results are looking great.
Your suggestion proved to be quite useful.
I'd like to participate in the procedure.
I've been a part of this project from day one.
I sourced the materials,
And I'm the one doing the culturing.
I'd like to be given the opportunity, Dr. Ko.
I'm not downplaying your contributions here.
But operating
Is a whole different issue.
We'll talk again once this project finds its footing.
By the way,
I'll be taking care of the supply of fetal stem cells from now on.
Thank you for your hard work.
But
Did you guys hear?
Apparently, Dr. Kang won't be a part of the project anymore.
- Are you serious? - He must still be in shock
After what happened to Hayun.
What's happening with the project then?
Dr. Choi will probably end up doing the surgeries again, right?
We've decided to put this project on hold.
What? On hold?
I'm not sure I understand.
We'll resume when Taeju comes back.
Dr. Ko, I can do the surgeries. Please reconsider--
It's been decided.
We're done here. You're dismissed.
Come on, pick up.
Pick up your phone, Noh Manhui.
Pick up your damn phone!
Come in.
Oh, Seyun.
What brings you here? :cue
Hmm
FUND DONATION AGREEMENT
CLINICAL TRIAL APPLICATION
I know everything.
Including the fetal stem cells.
Have a seat. Let's have a chat.
Just tell me.
I know.
I know it's not right.
But
I only did it to save the patients.
Saving patients?
You're right, it's important.
You always said,
"It's for the family, for the hospital, and for the patients."
But let me ask you, Dad.
Are you sure it wasn't all just for you?
You did this when Hayun died too.
I called for Taeju when Hayun was taken into the ER.
But you kept him from coming.
I didn't give up on Hayun.
It's just that he was in the middle of a procedure--
And whose procedure was it?
It was one of these people, wasn't it?
Who bought their place in line.
To you,
Family was never a priority.
That's not true.
Why do you think I did all of this?
It was all for you--
I know what you said to Taeju.
You told him to keep his mouth shut for me.
And you know what?
He was shouldering all the burden
That you and I should have been carrying.
Was that all for family too?
And now
There are too many things that can't be undone.
But still
We have to make right what we can.
And you have to be the one to do it.
FUND DONATION AGREEMENT CLINICAL TRIAL APPLICATION
You okay?
I'm sorry for making you carry this burden you never should have.
Stop saying that you're sorry.
You've had it much worse than I did.
We'll be okay, right?
Yeah. We'll be fine.
I'm going to make sure
That we'll be fine. :cue
DIRECTOR KANG TAEJU
Yeah, it's me, Kang Taeju.
Did you look into what I told you?
Yeah, we checked them.
But the parking lot connected through the fire doors doesn't have any cameras,
And there are plenty of blind spots nearby.
We ran the plates from every vehicle caught on camera
And cross-checked them against the hospital staff's plates,
But nothing matched.
Okay, got it.
Why won't you pick up your phone?
What did you do with Cha Myeonghui?
What about her?
Answer the damn question.
You took care of her, right?
I let her go.
You let her go?
You just let her go?
Yeah.
Are you insane? You can't just let her go like that!
I mean, what if she goes to the police? If she does, we'll both be screwed.
Maybe you will, not me.
That woman is not capable of doing whatever you're worried about.
Well,
She told me something very interesting.
What you told her is very different
From what you told me.
You believe what she told you?
Just take care of Kang Taeju already.
He's been digging everywhere.
I'll take care of it myself.
Are you not worried about your wife at all?
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
:cue
- I'll go check it out. - Yes, sir.
POLICE
-  What's going on? -  I'll go check it out.
I'll see what's going on over there.
I'll try to call them.
Hello?
Hello? Anyone there?
- What's the matter? - What's going on outside?
Is there a fire?
We're looking into it. Just wait.
Wait, officer!
Don't leave me all alone here. I'm handcuffed to the bed right now.
It'll just be a moment.
Hey!
What if I burn to death in this room?
What will you do then?
There were no signs of a fire within the hospital.
We checked the control room logs, and the fire alarm was set off manually.
Where's the control room?
It's located in B1.
What about cameras?
We don't have any cameras in that sector.
-  Captain. -  Yeah.
We did a full sweep of the hospital, but we didn't find anything suspicious.
We're searching the area too, but we haven't found anything.
And the officer who was guarding Kim Gyeongae's room
Said he was ambushed from behind.
He's regained consciousness, but he didn't see who it was.
We checked the surveillance footage too, but the alarm caused crowding,
So we haven't been able to identify anyone yet.
A fire alarm and an officer getting ambushed?
This was orchestrated.
Pull every visitor log for the hospital and call for backup.
- Yes, sir. - On it.
We can get you the entry logs.
Great, thank you.
The doors are opening.
Going up.
WING B
Where's my wife?
It wasn't me.
It wasn't you?
I know you took her.
I thought it was you.
Hey, look at me.
Look at me!
Look at me.
:cue
PYEONGWON FUNERAL HOME PYEONGWON NURSING HOME
BUSINESS CLOSED UNDER 24 HOUR PATROL
You
Why are you doing this?
Why the hell are you doing this?
What, you want revenge or something, Doctor?
Huh?
Say something. Why won't you answer me?
Say something, will you?
Why?
Are you scared?
Do you get it now?
How my wife must have felt in that room?
What the hell is that?
What are you doing?
Just an IV drip.
With a little bit of painkillers.
It hasn't been long since you had surgery.
You shouldn't move around too much.
You'll be here for a while.
Why did you put me in this place? What the hell are you trying to do?
My husband will not let you get away with this.
Got that?
Yeah, I know.
Look here.
Doctor!
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER :cue
- Hey. - Hey.
Do you think the hospital's cursed?
It's just one thing after another.
Tell me about it.
Have the cops not found Kim Gyeongae yet?
Yeah, it seems that way.
Where on earth did she go?
She probably can't even walk yet.
It has to be her husband, right?
Her husband?
You think he came in here, set off the alarm,
And took her under the cops' noses?
Why?
You think it's someone else?
Uh
They set off the fire alarm on purpose, so it had to be planned.
And they knew the blind spots.
It sounds like someone who knows the hospital inside and out, like us.
Hmm
If it's not her husband,
Why would anyone take her away?
Maybe they need her.
Why would they need her?
Maybe there was something
To be gained by taking her away from here.
Kang Taeju.
So it was you.
POTASSIUM CHLORIDE
I'll do it myself, then.
WING B
The doors are closing.
:cue
You took her, didn't you?
Where is my wife?
Don't worry, your wife's fine.
She's in a safe place.
A safe place?
Where's that? Huh?
Wherever she is, she's safer away from Choi Chiung, don't you think?
When you said I was the target, things started to click one by one.
As to why
Why you tried to kill me,
And why
He lied that your wife didn't make the cut because of her prior
And why she couldn't rat out Choi Chiung
Even though she knew he tried to kill her.
She didn't want to break off the deal.
He promised to get your wife that surgery in return for killing me.
I'll do that surgery.
The surgery Chiung promised you.
I'll do it.
What?
But I have a condition.
Turn yourself in.
Tell the cops everything Chiung told you to do.
And what makes you think I'd trust you?
You think you can trust Choi Chiung?
He will never hold up his end of the bargain.
It's your fault my wife didn't get her surgery, all right?
And now you want to do that surgery?
Says who?
Did Choi Chiung tell you that?
The choice is yours.
Turn yourself in, and your wife lives.
Let me know. I'll be waiting.
Says who?
Did Choi Chiung tell you that? :cue
Yes, come in.
Dr. Choi, this is the couple I talked to you about.
Come on in. Have a seat.
Have a seat, honey.
Why don't we catch up afterward, Dr. Cha?
Uh
Okay.
I bet you were crushed when you heard you didn't make it.
Well, it is what it is, I guess.
I thought it'd be best to be candid about this
And tell you the real reason you didn't get selected.
It's because of your criminal record, Ms. Kim.
But how would you know about that?
We run background checks on all applicants.
So, is there no way that my wife can get her surgery at all?
Uh Unless you have massive sums of money.
That tends to open up some doors.
So you're saying ex-cons with no money like me can just kick the bucket?
This is why I told you I wouldn't sign up.
But even if you had the money, it wouldn't work.
We're actually about to shut down this project.
What are you talking about?
The hospital director says he won't continue without his son-in-law.
His son-in-law?
A doctor named Kang Taeju is married to his daughter,
And he wanted out of the project.
He had no problem operating with illegal material
Until he realized he might take the heat.
So then the director decided that he'd call it quits after this round.
So this Kang Taeju is the reason my wife can't get her procedure?
And what's this illegal material anyway?
Well, this is sort of confidential,
But procedures like this
Usually require stem cells harvested from the patient's own body.
But the hospital director here
Decided it'd be better to get them from aborted fetuses.
What? Aborted fetuses?
It's despicable.
But it yields better results,
So they use it on the sly.
They do all this shady stuff,
But they deny your treatment just because you're an ex-convict.
You see, I've been a part of this project since day one.
I started before Kang, I've done more research and surgeries than he ever did.
But just because he's out
With Kang Taeju out of the picture
The director will eventually stop holding out
And resume the project.
And then I might be able to operate on Ms. Kim here as well.
You're saying if we got rid of him--
Hey.
You could save my wife, right?
Yes.
Get Kang Taeju out of the picture,
And I promise
I'll save your wife's life at all costs.
I hope you keep your word, Doctor.
Because if you don't, the rest of your life will be
A living hell.
I'll keep my word.
So will I. :cue
Yeah.
If I do as you tell me,
You'll operate on my wife, right?
And she'll
She'll get to live, right?
Don't worry. I'll do my best.
Keep your word.
I'll do as you say.
You better keep your word.
Don't you worry.
THE HUSBAND
Where is Ms. Kim Gyeongae?
If we leave her like this, she'll be paralyzed from the waist down.
The procedure that you wanted. It needs to be done now.
Everything Choi Chiung put me up to I have all the evidence.
Just do the surgery,
I'll hand it over and turn myself in.
I think you're forgetting that your wife's life is in my hands.
You know whose fault that is?
Today, you and your husband You're both dead.
I said let go!
I can't let you and your wife get off that easy.
Translated by Hyun Sik Yoon